ROBERT VERES

robertveres.com (980) 242-0057 Email: rwveres@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/robert-veres

U.S. Citizen

Proficient in English, Spanish, and Hungarian

Objective

Passionate, motivated student with six years of self-taught software development experience seeking to expand experience with front and back-end web technologies in a professional work environment. Enthusiastic collaborator and learner driven by attention to detail.

Skills

Full Stack Web Development

Multiple years of experience with developing, testing, and deploying web applications with the latest Back and Front-end frameworks.

Computer Architecture/IOT

Experience with Arduino microcontroller/Raspberry Pi IOT development, Intel x86 assembly, and low-level digital logic structures.

Data Science/Machine Learning

Data analysis, cleaning, and transformation skills to gain insight and train AI/ML models from large datasets with popular Python tools.

Technologies

Programming Languages/Environments: C, C#, .NET, Java, Python, PHP, Go, Dart, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, XML, XAML, Sass/SCSS, SQL

Frameworks/Tools: jQuery, Angular, React, Bootstrap, Django, Flask, ASP.NET (Core, MVC, Web API), NodeJS, Express, Progressive Web Apps, IndexedDB, PostreSQL, MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server, Redis, MongoDB, Memcached, Pandas, NumPy, Jupyter, Scikit-Learn, TensorFlow, Android Studio, Xamarin.Forms, React Native, Flutter, Visual Studio, SQL Server Management Studio, VMWare Workstation, Apache, IIS, Google Cloud Platform, Amazon Web Services, Firebase

Experience

FOUNDER & PRESIDENT - TANULJ KÓDOLNI (LEARN TO CODE) - June 2016 - Present

- Created the first online resource where Hungarian speakers can learn programming and software development for free.
- Developed back-end using ASP.NET Core MVC with Microsoft SQL Server and Entity Framework, implemented MVC and REST API patterns for smooth application flow, and added JWT user authentication with ASP.NET Identity.
- Developed **dynamic** Classroom front-end with HTML5, **ReactJS**, and React Material UI, implemented YouTube APIs, and added **single page application** navigation using React Router.
- Utilized Git/GitHub for version control and launching releases on DigitalOcean via TeamCity and Octopus.
- Made videos teaching programming in Python, creating a community of course developers, and promoting platform.

INSTRUCTOR - MATHNASIUM SOUTH CHARLOTTE - Charlotte, NC - February 2018 - Present

- Tutoring students in math from first through eighth grades (basic numerical concepts to algebra and geometry).
- Responsible for helping students with homework, **teaching new mathematical concepts**, and maintaining an engaging learning environment.
- Trained in tutoring for NC Standardized Tests (EOGs), worked with students to prepare for such exams.
- Collaborating with co-workers to ensure the best experience possible for students.

LEAD DEVELOPER - SANDLINE - Charlotte, NC - November 2017 - February 2018

- Coordinated with school administrators to help alleviate the congestion in school lunch line by building prototype for lunch request web application.
- Built REST API with NodeJS/Express and Loopback, incorporated a custom hashing and validation mechanism for secure in-memory data storage.
- Built responsive front-end tailored for mobile devices using Angular and Angular Material, implemented Angular reactive forms and validation for optimal user experience.

FOUNDER & PRESIDENT - PDS HACK CLUB - Charlotte, NC - November 2016 - Present

- Founder and leader of school's Computer Science/Hack Club, ensured growth to over 20 members.
- Holding lectures and developing resources (presentations, live demos) to teach club members interested in software about web, mobile app, and game development.
- Organized and launched first hackathon (Local Hack Day) at school in coordination with Major League Hacking.
- Collaborating with and contributing to the Hack Club community, an international organization promoting student-led coding clubs, by **expanding Computer Science curriculum** and **aiding in feature development**.

Awards

- NC Level 3 Regional Math Contest 2nd Place
- Appalachian State University Model UN Conference Best Delegate (2016, 2017, 2018, 2019)
- Pacific Rim Model UN Conference (Japan) Best Delegate
- National Merit Scholar Semifinalist
- National AP Scholar, AP Scholar with Distinction
- Providence Day Harvard Book Award (2019)

- Providence Day Cum Laude Society Chief Junior Marshall (2019)
- NC Science Olympiad Regional Competition: Top four finisher in all four events, Ecology 3rd Place (2018), Designer Genes 1st, Protein Modelling 2nd
- NC Science Olympiad State Competition: Designer Genes 4th (2019)
- CISAA All-Conference Cross-Country Athlete (2016, 2017, 2018, 2019)
- NCISAA Cross-Country State Championship Team (2016, 2017, 2018)

Education

PROVIDENCE DAY SCHOOL - Charlotte, NC - August 2014 - Present

- Advanced science and technology tracks, 4.711 Cumulative GPA, Head of School's List for five consecutive years.
- Combined SAT Score: 1600 (800 Reading and Writing/800 Math, 99th percentile).
- A+ in AP Computer Science Java and AP Computer Science Principles, 5 on AP Computer Science Principles and AP Computer Science A (Java) Exam.
- Charlotte Entrepreneurship Challenge: developed Business Plan for a Precision Agriculture Startup.
- Extracurricular Activities: Founder and President of Providence Day School Hack Club, international Model United
 Nations award winner and club officer, Honor Council senior member, Varsity Cross-Country (ranked in US overall top
 fifty) and Track, Spanish Language Society member, National Honor Society, Urban Farming.

EDX/COURSERA/MIT OCW/UDACITY - Online - 2013 - Present

- Self-taught and took online courses to develop skills and pursue passions for projects both in and outside of school.
- Online undergrad courses completed: MIT 18.01: Single Variable Calculus, MIT 18.02: Multivariable Calculus, MIT Highlights of Calculus, MIT 18.06: Linear Algebra, Harvard Statistics 110: Probability, MIT 18.650: Statistics for Applications, Coursera/Duke University: Bayesian Statistics, Harvard University CS50: Introduction to Computer Science, Harvard University CS 164: Software Engineering, Harvard University CS E-1: Understanding Computers and the Internet, MIT 6.858: Computer Systems Security, Carnegie Mellon 15-213: Introduction to Computer Systems, Carnegie Mellon 18-447: Introduction to Computer Architecture, Carnegie Mellon 15-688: Practical Data Science, Stanford CS229: Machine Learning, Stanford CS231N: Convolutional Neural Networks, Financial Institutions and Markets (Michigan State Univ.).
- Udacity: Full-Stack Web Development, Google App Engine, Progressive Web Apps (PWAs), Git/GitHub, Relational
 Databases, MongoDB, Front-End Frameworks, Linux Command Line, Android Development, iOS Development with Swift,
 Firebase, Data Science with NumPy and Pandas, Artificial Intelligence/Machine Learning.
- Microsoft Virtual Academy: MEAN (MongoDB, ExpressJS, Angular, NodeJS) Stack Development, NoSQL Databases (MongoDB/Redis), Flask, Django, ASP.NET MVC, ASP.NET MVC Core, ASP.NET Identity, Entity Framework, Bootstrap, Advanced JavaScript development, Xamarin.Forms development, Azure.